Dr.J.Jagatheesh Jayanand

Ardent Learner I Researcher I Passionate Knowledge Facilitator

Summary

An Ardent Learner and a Passionate Knowledge facilitator involved in research and Imbibing management principles from ancient scriptures, converting them to teachable point of view for application in day to day life of management practitioners.

Jagatheesh has experience in different domains handling multiple roles including Sales, Pre Sales, Solution Architecting, Distribution, Brand Management, ERP Implementations, Learning and Knowledge Management. Passionate about Sharing knowledge, looking forward to continue contributing to the society without any "I+I Want".

Experience

Senior Manager/Vice President - Learning and Knowledge Management at Accenture

April 2016 - Present (1 year)

As a Senior Manager with Learning and Knowledge Management team my current responsibilities Include:

- Encouraging Learning on and through NEW IT
- Deliver Design Thinking Sessions as a Coach for Design Thinking Workshops
- Active participant in the team in conceptualizing and designing "Innovation Curriculum"
- Strategize and conceptualize "Pre Learning"

Senior Manager/Vice President - SAP Sales Enablement Team at Accenture

August 2015 - April 2016 (9 months)

As a Senior Manager in Sales Enablement Team my responsibilities were Solution Architecting SAP System Integration deals. I was responsible for Sales Support and Solution Architecting for SI opportunities:

Worked with Clients on Multiple Opportunities Around:

- Conceptualized, Implemented strategic decisions resulting in securing large contracts for the organization
- Managing large verticals and accounts as part of solution architecting and pre sales
- Large outsourcing pursuits, interactions with deal consultants
- Business Case derivation
- Working on proposal response, pricing outcomes, client discussions and contract negotiation

- Delivery risk management
- Orals preparation and participation
- -Negotiation support and deal closure
- Participation in Contracting and help define PMO and underpinning contracts with 3rd party vendors
- Process harmonization and normalization across various lines of business

Senior Manager/Vice President - SAP Sales Enablement Team at Accenture

June 2007 - July 2015 (8 years 2 months)

As a Senior Manager in Solution Architecting Team my responsibilities were Solution Architecting SAP System Integration deals. I was responsible for Sales Support and Solution Architecting for SI opportunities:

Worked with Clients on Multiple Opportunities Around:

- IT & Sourcing Strategy & Execution
- Outsourcing Project Delivery (Solution, Transition, Execution)
- Near & Offshore Development
- Large outsourcing pursuits, interactions with deal consultants
- Set up solution architecting team and center of excellence
- Estimation techniques
- Delivery risk management
- Business Case derivation
- Orals preparation and participation
- Participation in Contracting and help define PMO and underpinning contracts with 3rd party vendors
- Process harmonization and normalization across various lines of business

Functional Consultant-SAP SD at Wipro Technologies

January 2005 - June 2007 (2 years 6 months)

Functional Consultant -SAP SD at Accenture

January 2004 - January 2005 (1 year 1 month)

Assistant Manager Marketing at ACC Cements

March 2002 - January 2004 (1 year 11 months)

Executive-Product at Saud Bahwan Group LLC

May 2001 - February 2002 (10 months)

Executive-Sales at Larsen & Toubro Limited

April 1999 - May 2001 (2 years 2 months)

Product Executive at Tenneco

April 1998 - April 1999 (1 year 1 month)

Certifications

SAP Solution Consultant

SAP AG October 2003

Publications

Mapping Competencies Of ERP* Functional Consultants- Regression Analysis Approach

British Journal of Economics, Finance and Management Sciences December 2015

Authors: Dr.J.Jagatheesh Jayanand, Dr.M.Senthil

Competency Model For Analyzing Competencies Of ERP* Functional Consultants- A Building Block Approach

Journal of American Academic Research October 2015

Authors: Dr.J.Jagatheesh Jayanand, DR.M.Senthi

Knowledge Management -Training workforce from bottom of the Pyramid to deliver ERP Functional Consulting roles in Technology Firms: Challenges and Experience

British Academy of Management 2013 Conference September 10, 2013

Authors: Dr.J.Jagatheesh Jayanand, Dr.M.Senthil

Published in British Academy of Management Conference Proceedings held on 11th September 2013 at University of Liverpool

Brand - Art Thou Maya?

Department of Management Studies . NIT Trichy February 2013

Authors: Dr.J.Jagatheesh Jayanand, Ilankumaran G, Dr.M.Senthil

Published in Edited Volumes of the Proceedings at - National Conference on Recent Trends in Marketing - Opportunities and Challenges at NIT Trichy on 20th February 2013

Competency Factors and Related Experience Indicators Of ERP Functional Consultants In India

International Journal of Business and Management Studies January 1, 2013

Authors: Dr.J.Jagatheesh Jayanand, Dr.M.Senthil

Presented at the International Journal of Arts and Sciences Conference held at Harvard University ,Boston on 27th May 2012

Computer Simulation, Analysis and Experimental Investigation On A Large Single Basin Solar Still

Applied Systems Research December 1995

Authors: Dr.Asok, Govind Jeyaram, Dr.J.Jagatheesh Jayanand, Mr.Saravanababu, Mr.Suryaprakash,

Mr.Senthil, Mr.Senthilkumar

Management Education and Human Values - Beyond Curriculum : Teaching Human Values in Management Education

Chapter in a Book - To be Published March 1, 2016

Authors: Dr.J.Jagatheesh Jayanand, Ganesh Babu, Sivakumar venkatachalam

A Chapter carrying information on a program conceptualized, designed and delivered to students in a Government University.

Book In Print Currently To Be Published by April 2017

Organizations

Department of Management Studies, Alagappa University

Member - Board of Studies

April 2012 to April 2014

Academy of Management

Member

May 2012 to Present

British Academy Of Management

Member

October 2012 to Present

Skills & Expertise

Business Development

Pre-sales

Consulting

Market Research

SAP ERP

Business Analysis

Business Process

Management Education

Business Intelligence

Management

Requirements Analysis

People Management

Integration

Team Management

Outsourcing

SAP Products

Team Building

Education

Madurai Kamaraj University

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Sales and Marketing, 1996 - 1998

Grade: First

Alagappa University

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Technology Management, 2010 - 2015

Mepco Schlenk Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Mechanical Engineering, 1992 - 1996

Grade: First Class

Kshatriya Vidyasala Matriculation Higher Secondary School

HigherSecondary, 1990 - 1992

SeventhDay Adventist Matriculation Higher Secondary School

Matriculation, 1978 - 1990

Volunteer Experience

Expert - Research and Knowledge Sharing at Sudar- An Initiative to Empower Student CommunityJune 2005 - Present

- -Based in Research conceptualize Design, Develop and Deliver sessions for student community empowering them to become Efficient in what they want to deliver in the Industry
- -Trained >4000 students over a period of 11 years and concentrated towards supporting students in rural part of the country.
- Working with Social organizations in Coaching/Training/Mentoring Youngsters to have a nation which has empowered youth with right direction

Dr.J.Jagatheesh Jayanand

Ardent Learner I Researcher I Passionate Knowledge Facilitator



1 person has recommended Dr.J.Jagatheesh

"Jagatheesh is an excellent team-player. He is a profound thinker. Highly competent and very good customer management. This makes him an ideal choice in every project."

— **Giridharan S**, *Senior Delivery Manager*, *Wipro Technologies*, managed Dr.J.Jagatheesh at Wipro Technologies

Contact Dr.J.Jagatheesh on LinkedIn